And that's your biggest worry? Yes, any kind of virus,
－那就是你最担心的事  －对 任何一种病毒
but most probably something similar to influenza.
但最可能是类似流感的东西
Because of air travel.
因为空中旅行
Through the air. - Coughing--
透过空气传播 像是咳嗽
- I'm sorry. I meant people. On planes.
－还有… －不好意思 我是指人们搭乘飞机
That was something you described in your book.
你的书里有提到
Yes, a new virus in Madagascar, say, could be in Chicago within a matter of weeks.
没错 马达加斯加的新病毒 可能会在几周内传到芝加哥
And we end up with a global pandemic. Pan meaning "all."
最后造成全球性的大流行病
The whole world becomes sick all at once.
意思就是全世界的人都同时染疫
And, Dr. Neuman, you're also an epidemiologist.
纽曼博士 你也是流行病学家
I presume the prospect of a viral pandemic keeps you up at night as well.
我想病毒造成大规模疫情的可能性 也让你辗转难眠吧
- No. - No?
－并没有 －是吗
- No. - All right, well, that's our show.
－并没有 －好吧 今天节目就到这里
No, mankind has been at war with the virus from the start.
不 人类一直以来都在与病毒交战
Sometimes, millions of people die, as in an actual war.
有时甚至和真正的战争一样 死亡人数高达数百万
But in the end, we always win.
但到头来 我们永远是赢家
But you-- just to be clear, you do think microorganisms pose a threat.
我们先厘清一点 你确实认为微生物是种威胁
In the most dire terms.
是很严峻的威胁
- Bacteria. - No.
－细菌  －不是
- You like saying no. - Yes.
－你喜欢否定别人 －没错
Not bacteria. Not viruses. - So?
不是细菌 不是病毒 所以是…
- Fungus.
真菌
Yes, that's the usual response.
没错 这是常见的反应
Fungi seem harmless enough.
真菌似乎挺无害的
Many species know otherwise.
许多物种却知道事实并非如此
Because there are some fungi who seek not to kill,
因为有些真菌寻求的不是杀戮
but to control.
而是控制
Let me ask you, where do we get LSD from?
我问你 迷幻药是从哪里来的
Where do you get it from?
你又是从哪里拿到的
It comes from ergot, a fungus.
它来自麦角 一种真菌
Psilocybin? Also a fungus.
还有神奇蘑菇 也是真菌
Viruses can make us ill, but fungi can alter our very minds.
病毒会让我们生病 但真菌能改变我们的心智
There's a fungus that infects insects.
有一种真菌会感染昆虫
Gets inside an ant, for example,
比方说入侵蚂蚁的身体
travels through its circulatory system to the ant's brain,
透过循环系统进入蚂蚁的大脑
and then floods it with hallucinogens, thus bending the ant's mind to its will.
让大脑充满迷幻药 从而使蚂蚁的心智屈服于其意志
The fungus starts to direct the ant's behavior,
真菌开始指挥蚂蚁的行为
telling it where to go, what to do,
告诉它该去哪里 该做什么
like a puppeteer with a marionette.
就像操偶师操纵牵线木偶那样
And it gets worse.
而且情况还会更糟
The fungus needs food to live,
真菌需要食物才能存活
so it begins to devour its host from within,
所以它会开始从体内吞噬宿主
replacing the ant's flesh with its own,
用自己的组织取代蚂蚁的肉体
but it doesn't let its victim die.
但它不会让受害者死去 不
No, it keeps its puppet alive by preventing decomposition.
它会防止受害者腐烂 让傀儡继续活下去
How?
怎么办到
Where do we get penicillin from? Fungus.
－盘尼西林从哪里来  －真菌
Dr. Schoenheiss, you're in distress. Fungal infection of this kind is real,
－萧恩海斯博士 你不同意  －这种真菌感染确实存在
but not in humans.
但不会发生在人类身上
True, fungi cannot survive if its host's internal temperature is over 94 degrees.
没错 如果宿主的体内温度 超过华氏９４度
And currently,
真菌的确无法存活
there are no reasons for fungi to evolve
而且目前真菌没有理由
to be able to withstand higher temperatures.
进化到能够承受更高的温度
But what if that were to change? What if, for instance,
但要是情况改变了呢 譬如说…
the world were to get slightly warmer?
地球的温度稍微上升了一点
Well, now there is reason to evolve.
那就有进化的理由了
One gene mutates
只要出现一次基因突变
and an ascomycete, candida, ergot,
一种子囊菌 像是念珠菌 麦角
cordyceps, aspergillus,
虫草菌 曲菌等
any one of them could become capable of burrowing into our brains
任何一种都有可能钻进我们的大脑
and taking control not of millions of us, but billions of us.
进而控制人类 而且不是数百万人 是数十亿人
Billions of puppets with poisoned minds
数十亿个心智遭到毒害的傀儡
permanently fixed on one unifying goal:
永远锁定一个统一的目标
to spread the infection to every last human alive
用尽一切必要手段感染每一个…
by any means necessary.
还活着的人
And there are no treatments for this. No preventatives, no cures.
这种病没有治疗方法 没有预防措施 没有解药
They don't exist. It's not even possible to make them.
解药不存在 甚至不可能制造出来
So, if that happens?
所以如果发生那种事…
We lose.
我们就输了
We'll be back.
我们稍后回来
Alarm.
闹钟响了
- Where's the pancake mix?
松饼粉呢
- Oh, was I--
用完了吗
Yeah, I was. Sorry.
对 用完了 抱歉
I was gonna make you birthday pancakes. I swear.
我本来要帮你做生日松饼的 真是的
You know I don't really like pancakes.
我其实不喜欢松饼
I know you don't like them. It was for my benefit.
我知道你不喜欢 是我自己想吃
Vitamin C.
要补充维他命Ｃ
You get your homework done?
功课做完了吗
Fractions?
在学分数吗
How old are you again?
你现在是几岁
Thirty-six.
３６岁
Gonna have to wear diapers soon. Who says I don't already?
－很快就得穿尿布了 －谁说我还没穿
Shell. Calcium.
－有蛋壳 －补充钙质
Lovely.
很好
Is there enough for Uncle Tommy?
够汤米叔叔吃吗
Well, there would've been.
本来够的
You're still alive, you old fucker.
还活着啊 你这老混蛋
He loves you. He's dependent on me. Not the same.
－他爱你 －他靠我过活 这不一样
- I think it's the same. - It's definitely the same.
－我觉得一样 －绝对一样
I thought we was havin' pancakes.
我以为我们要吃松饼
We'll pick you somethin' up on the road.
我会在路上帮你买吃的
- Concrete guys gonna be there? - Yeah, they said maybe.
－水泥工也会去吗  －他们说也许会
Maybe? We can't frame until we pour. We're not gettin' paid until we frame.
也许 没灌浆就不能做构架 没构架就拿不到钱
Well, we could bring someone else on, get the job done faster.
可以找别人来 这样会更快完工
- No, no. I'm not splittin' this job.
不行 我不要跟别人合作这个案子
I barely wanna split it with you.
连跟你合作我都不太甘愿了
We could work a double.
我们可以加班
- Literally?
不是吧
Today? - I know. I'd be done by nine.
－今天加班  －我知道 我九点前会结束
By nine, right?
九点 对吧
Yeah.
对
I'll bring back a cake.
我会带蛋糕回来
I promise.
我保证
...continued disturbances in Jakarta, but are advising U.S. citizens...
雅加达持续发生动乱 政府仍建议美国公民…
Jakarta. Where is that, Middle East?
雅加达 那是哪里 中东吗
Doesn't ring a bell. It's definitely a country.
没印象 绝对是个国家
- Or maybe part of Asia?
或者是亚洲的一部分
- Jakarta isn't a country.
雅加达不是一个国家
Being a part of Asia isn't mutually exclusive with being a country,
作为亚洲的一部分 不代表一定不是国家
and in fact, it's the capital of Indonesia.
事实上 雅加达是印尼的首都
Shit. Hope for us yet.
天啊 看来未来还有希望
All right.
好
Finish up quick, we'll drop you off.
快点吃完 我们送你上学
- I'm still eating my eggshells. - You got seven minutes.
－我还在吃蛋壳 －你还有七分钟
Your t-shirt's inside out.
你的Ｔ恤里外穿反了
Shit.
该死
He's losin' it.
他要疯了
Sarah!
莎拉
Hey, neighbor!
你好 邻居
Oh, Hi.
你们好
Connie was askin' after you,
康妮问起你
since you haven't been over in a while.
因为你有一阵子没来了
Make 'em happy.
配合一下吧
I could come by after school, but just for, like, a little bit?
我放学后可以过去 但只能一下下
- She'll take whatcha got.
她都可以
Y'all can bake, whatever.
你们可以一起烘焙什么的
Speakin' of,
说到这个
we got a lotta extra here.
我们还有很多饼干
Y'all want some biscuits?
你们想来一点吗
Dad, you love biscuits.
爸 你最爱饼干了
I do.
没错
But I'm on Atkins.
但我在采取艾金斯饮食法
- On what now? - It's,
－什么东西  －就是…
you know what? We gotta run, but Sarah'll be by later.
你知道吗 我们得走了 但莎拉晚点会过去
She'll stay as long as you want.
你要她待多久都行
Tell ya all about Atkins. Great!
－她会跟你介绍艾金斯饮食法的一切 －太好了
I'll let Connie know.
我会转告康妮的
Solid.
算你狠
Can't tell you how exciting it was listenin' to that fuckin' conversation.
听到这样的对话还真是刺激啊
Put that out.
把烟熄掉
Happy birthday to you.
祝你生日快乐
OPERATION DESERT STORM COMBAT VETERAN
（沙漠风暴行动退伍军人）
AUSTIN, TX SEPTEMBER 26th
（德州 奥斯丁 ９月２６日）
Want you to write this diagram out exactly as I have it.
我要你们把这个图表 一字不漏地抄下来
Always subject and predicate.
一定要有主词 述词
Verb and noun.
动词和名词
Okay, the sentence is, "Where are you going?"
好 句子是“你要去哪里 ”
Subject is you.
主词是“你”
You are going.
“你要去”
Predicate. Where, adverb.
述词 “哪里” 副词
You see it? Okay. Have some nods, shaking of heads.
懂吗 好 我看到有些人点头 有些人摇头
I swear you will use this later in life.
我发誓你们以后一定会用到
Believe me, that's why you're here.
相信我 这就是为什么 我们现在要学这些
Okay? So...
“你”是主词 主词一定要接动词
Yes, you need to know this!
没错 你们一定要知道
Yes, it's on your test next week!
下星期的考试会考
Homework is due end of class tomorrow!
明天下课前要交作业
Twenty.
２０元
That's it?
就这样
Okay, 30.
好 那３０元
Twenty's good.
２０元可以
It's a spring. I'll do it right now.
是弹簧出了问题 我现在就修
All day. I swear.
整天都这样 真是的
We're closing.
我们要打烊了
We're done for today.
我们要关门了
It's 3:15, we close at 7.
现在才３点１５分 我们７点关门
- I'm very sorry. He cannot finish. - I'm already finished.
－我很抱歉 他没办法做完 －我已经修好了
You should go home.
你该回家了
- There you are, sweetie. - Sorry.
－你终于来了 亲爱的 －抱歉
I was gettin' worried.
我都开始担心了
I was getting something for my dad.
我去拿要给我爸的东西
Hi, Mercy.
你好 梅西
Hey, is everything okay?
一切都还好吧
Like, on the news?
有什么新闻吗
Like what, hon?
你是指什么 甜心
Well, no, there was just a lot of police and stuff on the road today.
也没什么 只是今天路上有很多警察
Well, that's true every day, innit?
每天都这样 不是吗
People out there need to get right with Jesus.
人们应该要向耶稣忏悔
Three nails, plus one cross, equals four-given.
三根钉子加一个十字架等于宽恕
I was thinkin' we'd make some cookies.
我们可以来做饼干
Chocolate chip?
巧克力碎片
Raisin.
葡萄干
C'mon, Mama.
吃啊 妈
It's green.
这是绿色的
You love that.
你最爱了
Here we go!
好了
I don't know why I talk to her.
我不知道为什么我要跟她说话
She's completely deaf.
她已经完全听不见了
You wanna give me a hand?
你要来帮我吗
Be right there!
马上来
Hey, Mrs. Adler?
艾德勒太太
Could I borrow this?
这个可以借我吗
Yeah, sure. It's one of Danny's.
当然可以 这是丹尼的
You know what? My dad's gonna be back real soon. - I should go.
我爸很快就会回来 我该走了
- You sure? - Yeah.
－你确定  －对
- Well, you're takin' some cookies.
你要带些饼干走
No comment today from the Austin Police Department regarding a rash of violent incidents across the city,
今天对城内爆发的一连串暴力事件 不予置评
some suggesting a new street drug may be to blame.
有人认为罪魁祸首 可能是新的街头毒品
More on that when we return,
稍后回来
with Manuela Sanchez reporting live...
记者曼纽拉桑切斯 将在总部进行现场报导
You locked the door for once.
你终于记得锁门了
Good job.
做得好
Yeah.
是啊
- It's 10. - I know.
－都十点了 －我知道
They gave us the wrong size for the headers.
他们给的顶梁尺寸不对
That doesn't mean anything to ya. I'm sorry.
那对你来说毫无意义 对不起
Where's the cake?
蛋糕在哪
- Shit.
该死
- C'mon, man. I'll get us one tomorrow.
－拜托 －我明天再买
Swear,
你发誓
or you don't get your present.
不然你就没礼物了
- You got me a present?
你为我准备了礼物
- Swear.
你先发誓
On my life.
以我的性命发誓
Wow.
瞧瞧
Fixed it for you.
我帮你修好了
- Did you? - What?
－有吗  －什么
I don't hear anything.
我什么都没听到
That was lame.
这招很逊
- You're lame. - Yeah, I know.
－你很逊 －对 我知道
Where'd you get the money for this?
你哪来的钱
Drugs. I sell hardcore drugs. It's better than what I do.
－我是药头 专卖强力毒品 －比我的工作强多了
It was only $20, which I stole from you.
才花了２０元 我从你那里偷来的
I could've stolen 60,
我本来可以偷６０元
but I put the change back because I'm an honest thief.
但我把零钱放回去了 因为我盗亦有道
Besides, it's the thought that counts.
而且 心意最重要
And you were never gonna do it for yourself, so.
你永远不会为自己这么做 所以…
Thank you.
谢谢你
There's one more.
还有一个
- Borrowed it from the Adlers.
跟艾德勒家借的
- This is the one with the deleted scenes. Yeah,
－这是有包含删减片段的 －对
imagine how bad those have to be.
想想是有多烂才会被删
C'mon, pop it in. While it's still your birthday.
开始播吧 趁现在还是你的生日
- Don't fall asleep.
别睡着了
-'Course, I won't. It's too riveting.
当然不会 那么精彩
Hello?
你好
Joel, it's me.
乔尔 是我
I'm okay.
我没事
- Yeah? -But I'm in jail.
－是吗  －但我在牢里
- Goddammit. -Wasn't my fault this time.
－该死 －这次不是我的错
I was at the bar, some guy goes crazy, starts swingin' at a waitress,
我在酒吧 有个家伙突然抓狂 开始殴打女服务生
I stepped in, knocked him out, cops show up--
我插手 把他打昏 警察就出现了
Look, it doesn't fuckin' matter. -You gotta bail me out.
听着 这不重要 你得保我出去
- Now? It's Friday,
－现在  －今天是星期五
you don't get me out tonight, I'm in here all weekend.
今晚你不保我出去 我整个周末都得待在这里
It's a fuckin' madhouse, Joel. -I gotta get out.
这里简直是疯人院 乔尔 我得出去
- Well, which jail? Travis County?
哪间看守所 崔维斯郡
Yeah, on 10th.
对 在第十街
- Goddammit, Tommy.
该死 汤米
-I'm sorry.
抱歉
Please.
拜托
Okay.
好吧
Fuckin' idiot.
该死的白痴
Dad?
爸
...indoors.
请待在室内
Law enforcement and emergency services are in the area
执法人员和紧急服务人员已经出动
and will be in contact with further instructions.
请等候进一步指示
Stay indoors,
请待在室内
law enforcement...
执法人员…
Easy. Easy, Mercy.
冷静点 梅西
What're you doing out here, boy?
你怎么会在这里
C'mon, let's get you home.
来 我带你回家
C'mon, Mercy. Please.
走吧 梅西 拜托
Mercy!
梅西
Mrs. Adler?
艾德勒太太
Help me.
救我
Get in the truck! Right now!
上车 快
Move!
快
What are we doin', Joel?
怎么办 乔尔
- You killed her. - Baby, I'm sorry.
－你杀了她 －宝贝 对不起
- Joel, we gotta go. - Sarah, listen to me.
－乔尔 我们得走了 －莎拉 听我说
It's not just the Adlers.
不只是艾德勒家这样
But we're gonna be brave, and we're gonna get outta this.
但我们要勇敢 我们会逃出去的
Hey. Let's go. Come on.
我们走吧 快
Get in.
上车
Joel?
乔尔
Denise, you get back inside the house!
丹妮丝 回屋里去
- You lock your doors! Now!
把门锁上 快点
- C'mon, c'mon, get in!
快点上车
- Get your seat belt on. - Hold on.
－系上安全带 －抓紧了
Jesus Christ, Joel!
天啊 乔尔
- You take 70-- - 71, I know.
－你走７１… －７１号公路 我知道
AUSTIN SAN MARCOS
（奥斯丁 圣马克斯）
- Daddy-- - We don't know.
－爸  －我们不知道
They're saying it's a virus. Some kind of parasite.
他们说是病毒或某种寄生虫
Is it from terrorists?
是恐怖分子干的吗
We don't know.
我们不知道
- Are we sick? - No. Of course not.
－我们也生病了吗  －不 当然没有
Why did things blow up? No cellphone, no radio.
－为什么都没有消息  －没有手机讯号 没有广播
Minute ago, newsman wouldn't shut up.
一分钟前新闻还报个不停
- How do you know? - What?
－你怎么知道  －什么
How do you know we're not sick?
你怎么知道我们没生病
They're saying it's mostly people in the city.
他们说大部分是市区的人受感染
That's why they got the highway blocked off.
所以他们才封锁高速公路
God.
天啊
It's Jimmy's place.
那是吉米家
The Adlers would take Nana into the city.
艾德勒家会带婆婆进城
To the hospital for stuff.
去医院看病
That's right. They would.
没错 他们会那么做
That's probably why.
那可能就是原因
But, you'd have to go a lot,
但要很常去才会得
right?
对吧
We're fine. Trust me.
你没事的 相信我
All right.
好
Here! Right here!
等等 慢一点 停车
- Hey! - What are you doin'? - Got a kid, Joel.
－你在干什么  －他们有小孩 乔尔
- So do we. Keep driving.
－我们也有 继续开 －等等 请停车
We could put them in the back.
－我们可以让他们坐后面 －不…拜托
Somebody else'll come along.
会有其他人经过的
Fuck! Everybody had the same fuckin' idea.
该死 每个人都打着一样的主意
I can't get through this. All right. Let's think it through, we'll think it through.
－我过不去 －好 我们好好想想
- Fuck! - All right, take the field.
－该死 －走空地
We cut across and we pick up on the west side.
我们切过去从西边上公路
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. West, west, all right. All right, hang on.
好…西边…好 坐稳了
Shit! Fuckin' army.
可恶 是该死的军队
- Isn't that good?
那不是好事吗
- It's good for them, but that's the highway we're tryin' to get to.
对他们来说是好事 但那是我们要走的公路
All right, keep movin'. Head north. - Could be a lotta people.
－继续开 往北走 －会有很多人
- Well, we can't go south, we can't go east, we can't go west.
我们不能往南 不能往东 不能往西
Hell else we supposed to go?
不然我们还能去哪
Tommy, come on!
汤米 快点
Yeah.
对
Yeah, I know that place. - This can work. - Yeah, but then what?
－这地方我认得 应该行得通 －但然后呢
I don't know. Mexico. Just far, far as we can. - How much gas?
我不知道 去墨西哥 越远越好 还剩多少汽油
- Three-quarter tank.
－四分之三油箱 －好
Go through town, golf course by the river, straight across,
我们走市区 穿过河边的高尔夫球场
we pick up the highway on the other side of the blockade, then we're out.
在路障的另一边接上高速公路 然后我们就脱身了
Maybe it's everywhere.
也许已经蔓延到各地了
Maybe there's nowhere to go.
也许我们无处可去
What the fuck?!
搞什么
Son of a bitch. Gotta go around.
该死 得要绕过去
Grab somethin'!
抓稳
All right, keep goin', keep goin'.
－该死 看看他们 －好 继续走…
Shit. Tommy!
－该死 －汤米
Tommy, you can't stop here.
汤米 你不能停在这里
- I can't drive through 'em all. - Are you serious?
－我没办法撞过去 －你是认真的吗 继续开
Just keep goin'!
好啦
Go, go, go. Back, back, back, back, back, back, back! - I'm trying!
－倒车… －我在试了
Tommy, go faster! We gotta go! I'm tryin'! There's nowhere to fuckin' go!
－汤米 快点 我们要赶快离开 －我在试了 没地方可去
- Find an alley! - What alley? - There's people everywhere!
－找条巷子 －什么巷子 到处都是人
- Roll the fuck over them! We gotta get off this street now!
从他们身上辗过去 我们得立刻离开这条街
That's what I'm tryin' to do, Joel.
我正在努力那么做 乔尔
We're gonna be okay. Just keep drivin'.
我们会没事的 继续前进就好
Dad?
爸
Holy shit!
该死
Move. Move!
快走…
Sarah, Sarah. Stay right there. Don't move.
莎拉…待在那里别动
Tommy, you okay? Yeah, I'm okay.
－汤米 你没事吧  －我没事
Sarah, don't look.
莎拉 别看
You look at me, okay?
看着我就好 好吗
I'm sorry, baby, I know, I know. Come here. Put your arms around me.
抱歉 宝贝 我知道很痛 我知道
Come here, come here.
抱着我 来…
I got you. I got you.
我抱住你了…
Got you.
我抱住你了
Are you okay? Are you okay?
你还好吗 没事吧
- My ankle. - All right, okay.
－我的脚踝 －好
We gotta get off the street!
我们得离开这条街
Shit!
该死
Tommy?!
汤米
Head to the river! I'll find a way.
去河边 我会自己想办法
Get her outta here, Joel! Go!
带她离开 乔尔 快走
- We can't leave him. - He'll be fine. - Can you run?
－我们不能丢下他 －他不会有事的 你能跑吗
- No.
不行
- You keep your eyes on me. - Okay.
－眼睛看着我 好吗  －好
- Okay? - Okay. And don't look anywhere else.
－好 －别看其他地方
Alright.
好
It's okay, baby. You're safe.
没事了 亲爱的 你安全了
Don't move!
不准动
- My daughter's hurt. Her ankle. - Stop right there!
－我女儿受伤了 她的脚踝… －站住
Okay.
好
Easy now. We're not sick!
放轻松 我们没病
I got two civilians by the river, one of 'em injured.
河边有两个平民 一人受伤
Ankle.
脚踝
What about Uncle Tommy?
汤米叔叔怎么办
We're gonna get you somewhere safe first.
我们先让你到安全的地方
Then we'll go back for him, okay? - Okay.
－然后再回去找他 好吗  －好
- Okay.  I'm sorry, repeat?
－好 －抱歉 再说一次
Hey! No one told you to move.
站住 谁叫你们动了
Yes, sir.
是 长官
We're not sick.
我们没有病
Sir,
长官
I'm sorry.
对不起
Please, don't.
拜托不要
Oh God.
天啊
No. Oh no.
不
No, no. No.
不…
Okay, You're okay.
好 你没事的
You're okay. Move your hand, baby.
你没事 手拿开 宝贝
Move your hand.
手拿开
I know, baby, I know, I know, I know, I know.
不 我知道 宝贝 我知道…
I know it hurts.
我知道很痛
Alright. Don't look down, look up, look up.
好了 来…
Come on, baby. You're okay, you're okay.
加油 宝贝 你没事的
I know, I know, I know, I know, baby, I know, I know.
我知道…宝贝 我知道…
I know this hurts.
我知道很痛
You're gonna be okay.
你会没事的 好吗
All right, baby, baby, baby, listen to me.
宝贝…听我说
I gotta get you up, okay?
我得扶你起来 好吗
I gotta get you up. All right?
我得扶你起来 可以吗
You come on. You come on.
来…
I know, baby.
我知道 宝贝
No, no. I know, I know, I know, I know, I know, I know.
我知道…
Tommy, help me!
汤米 帮帮我
Joel.
乔尔
C'mon, baby girl. C'mon, baby girl, I gotta get you up. Come on.
来 宝贝女儿 我得扶你起来 快
Come on, we'll get up. Come on, baby girl.
来 我们得走了 快点 宝贝女儿
Come on,
拜托
come-- Please.
拜托…求求你
TWENTY YEARS LATER
（二十年后）
BOSTON
（波士顿）
WELCOME
（欢迎）
We don't want you falling out of the chair.
我们不希望你从椅子上摔下来
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Are you alone?
你一个人吗
And,
还有…
how did you get this?
这是怎么了
There's gonna be a little tickle right here.
这里会有点痒
What if I told you that after we gave you some medicine,
如果我告诉你 在我们给你一些药之后
we're gonna find you your favorite food to eat.
我们会给你你最爱吃的食物怎么样
Would you like that?
你想吗
And then we'll get you some new clothes... and toys.
然后我们会给你些新衣服和玩具
As many as you wanna play with.
你想玩多少就玩多少
It's just a little needle.
只是个小针头
It's okay.
没事的
You're safe.
你很安全
I can't.
我做不到
Ten.
十张
- You got anything else?
有别的工作吗
- Nothin' today. Tomorrow, we got street sweeping,
今天没有 明天有清扫街道
or sewer maintenance.
或维护下水道
Which pays more?
哪个薪水比较高
That'd be the one with the shit.
会碰到大便的那个
Late crew. 4 P.M. start.
晚班 下午四点开始
CURFEW HOURS 6PM - 6AM
（宵禁时间 晚上六点至早上六点）
ANYONE ON THE STREET WITHOUT FEDERAL APPROVAL IS SUBJECT TO IMMEDIATE ARREST
（未经允许外出 将被立即逮捕）
SHOE LACES 1 RATION CARD EACH BOOT LACES 2 RATION CARDS EACH SEARCH FOR THE LIGHT
（鞋带 一张配给卡 靴带 两张配给卡）
Jason Choi, violation of EMC 342.3,
杰森蔡 违反环境管理条约 第３４２点３条
unauthorized exit from a Quarantine Zone.
未经授权离开隔离区
Maria Elisiano, violation of EMC 342.7,
玛丽亚艾利西安诺 违反环境管理条约第３４２点７条
unauthorized entry into a Quarantine Zone.
未经授权进入隔离区
Each of you have been tried in a military court of justice,
你们每一位皆已在军事法庭受审
and each of you having been found guilty by the court martial panel,
并被军法审判团判处有罪
and with a sentence of death by execution,
处以死刑
as empowered under the EMPA, Article 1, Section 5...
根据环境管理与保护法案 第一条第五点…
C'mon.
快点
Or I could just shoot you. Yeah, but then what would you do?
－我也可以直接开枪打死你 －对 但然后你要怎么办
You're short five.
你还少五张
- Oxy? - Hydro.
－奥施康定  －氢可酮
- How old? - Three months.
－多久以前的  －三个月
- From Atlanta? - I don't know where he gets 'em from.
－亚特兰大来的  －我不知道他从哪弄来的
I just know they're real. If it's real, it's from Atlanta.
－我只知道是真的 －如果是真的 就来自亚特兰大
FEDRA's got a factory down there in the QZ.
联邦灾害对策局 在那里的隔离区有间工厂
Supposedly only makes two things.
据说只生产两种东西
Pills and bullets, bullets and pills.
药丸和子弹 子弹和药丸
Well, the more you shoot people, the harder it is to sleep, I guess.
我猜你越常对人开枪就越难入睡
You guess?
“你猜”
You want 'em or not?
你到底要不要
I need the bag back.
袋子要还给我
- How we doin' with the vehicle? - All set.
－车子怎么样了  －都准备好了
Just had to get one last guy in the depot to buy in.
只差仓库最后一个人需要买通
Okay, how much?
好 要多少
Four of them on that shift plus me... six hundred total.
那一班有四个人 加上我 总共六百
Look, those trucks are shitheaped for a reason.
听着 那些卡车会被报废是有原因的
And they don't have any batteries. I know.
它们没有电池 我知道
I can see about 200 for the other guys... two hundred for you.
我可以给其他人两百 你单独两百
Deal.
成交
Hey, do yourself a favor,
对了 帮你自己一个忙
stay off the streets for the next few nights.
接下来几晚别上街
Fuckin' Fireflies been blowin' shit up all week.
该死的火萤整周都在到处乱炸
Two of our guys got shot this morning. Boss has got us working doubles.
早上我们有两个人中弹 老大要我们连值两班
Guys are jumpy and tired.
大家都又紧张又累
It's easy to make a mistake in the dark.
在黑暗中很容易失手
Stay safe.
注意安全
Yeah, you too.
你也是
WHEN YOU'RE LOST IN THE DARKNESS LOOK FOR THE LIGHT
（当你迷失在黑暗中时 就寻找光明）
What do you want me to say, Tess?
你要我说什么 泰丝
I'm not askin' you to say anything.
我没有要你说什么
Sure.
最好是
It's not like I planned
我又不是故意…
on rippin' you off.
要骗你的
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Well,
好
how about we just let it go?
不如我们放下这件事吧
What else are you gonna do?
不然你要怎样
Ya gonna keep me here? - Kill me?
你要把我关在这里吗 杀了我
- Tess, c'mon. Then, Robert, what do ya want?
－泰丝 拜托 －那罗伯特 你想怎样
I want you to forget this ever happened. Done.
－我要你忘记这件事 －没问题
- Don't do that. - What? It's just a truck battery.
－你少来 －怎么了 不过是卡车电池罢了
I paid you for it, you sold it to someone else, and you spent my money.
我付钱跟你买 你卖给别人 还花掉我的钱
I mean, you think I've never done shit like that?
你以为我没干过这种鸟事吗
- My guys fucked you up. - Yeah, so discipline them.
－我的人把你揍惨了 －对 那就管管他们
You cut off a finger or whatever the fuck you want.
切掉一根手指或随便你想怎样
I don't care. They're your fuckin' guys.
我不在乎 他们是你的人
What about your guy?
那你的人呢
'Cause when he sees you, - I mean, put yourself in my shoes.
等他看到你这副样子 你站在我的立场想想
- Look, he answers to me.
听着 他对我唯命是从
So, I give you my word that he won't hurt you.
所以我向你保证 他不会伤害你
I'll tell him that I got jumped by some guys,
我会跟他说我被几个家伙打了
and then you and I can just move the fuck on.
然后你跟我就可以继续过日子了
Now your shit has pretty much ruined my week,
你干的好事已经毁了我这一周
and I'd like to go home and drink 'til my face stops hurting.
我只想回家喝酒 喝到脸不痛为止
So, are we good?
我们没事了吧
Yeah.
对
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
所有市民必须立即撤离周遭区域
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
在联邦灾害对策局许可前不得返回
Oh shit.
该死
Firefly, up top!
火萤来了
Free Boston now, motherfuckers!
现在就解放波士顿 混蛋
- They're shooting. They're shooting at us. - On your knees. - On your knees!
－他们在开枪 他们在对我们开枪 －跪下…
- No, no! I'm not a F--
不 我不是…
I'm not a Firefly!
我不是…我不是火萤的人
Count slowly and clearly from one to 10. - One, two, three, four--
－慢慢清楚地从一数到十 －一 二 三 四…
- Slowly, and clearly.
慢慢数 数清楚
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
Four.
四
Five.
五
Six.
六
Seven.
七
Eight.
八
Fuck... you.
去你的
And hold out your--
现在伸出你的…
- State your name, slowly and clearly. - Veronica.
－慢慢说出你的名字 －薇若妮卡
Same as yesterday, and the day before,
跟昨天一样 还有前天
and the day before, and the--
还有大前天 还有…
Hey, people are gonna come looking for me. People from FEDRA. You hear me?
会有人来找我的 对策局的人 听到了吗
Let me out or you're gonna pay, motherfuckers!
放我出去 不然你们会付出代价 混蛋
I'm not supposed to be here!
我不该在这里的
WHEN YOU'RE LOST IN THE DARKNESS
（当你迷失在黑暗中时）
Hey, there's a line!
听着 要排队
"Tell Dad it's a girl.
“告诉爸是个女孩”
"That would be good, right?
“这是好事 对吧 ”
"He wanted a granddaughter. Love, Becca."
“你想要孙女 爱你的贝卡”
End message. Read back.
留言结束 念出来
Correct, 73-K Orlando. Out.
正确 ７３Ｋ奥兰多通话完毕
Nothin'?
没消息
Is there any chance it's comin' in at night? You're sleepin', you miss it?
有没有可能是晚上传来的  你睡着所以漏掉了
When I'm sleeping, Gabriela listens, or my son.
我睡觉时 会由盖比瑞拉或我儿子负责监听
The smart one, not the other one, God bless him.
聪明的那个 不是另一个 上帝保佑他
If Tommy responded, we'd know.
如果汤米有回应 我们会知道的
- And you're talkin' to the tower?
你有跟塔台联络
- Every day. They gave him your message, they haven't seen or heard from him since,
每天都有 他们把你的留言转给他后 就再也没有他的消息了
and that's it.
就这样
- It hasn't been that long. - It's been three weeks.
－其实也不算很久 －已经三周了
It's never taken him more than a day to respond.
他从来不会超过一天才回覆
I'm sure he's okay.
我相信他没事的
Show me where the tower is.
告诉我塔台在哪里
You can't be serious.
你不是认真的吧
Joel, it's in Wyoming.
乔尔 那在怀俄明州
All this open country?
你得要长途跋涉
I mean, you're a capable guy, but there are worse things than Infected out there.
你是很厉害 但外面有比感染更糟糕的事
I hear everything on this. There are raiders, there are slavers--
我全都听到了 有盗匪 有奴隶贩子
But you're "sure" Tommy's okay?
但你确定汤米没事
It's the Cody tower... Q-Bar 4,
是科迪塔 Ｑ４
but I don't know exactly wh--
但我不知道确切位置…
Next!
下一位
You know what, Joel...
你知道吗 乔尔
Joel!
乔尔
I got jumped by a couple guys.
我被几个家伙打了
- What guys? - Just a couple teenagers.
－什么人  －只是几个青少年
Said some shit, probably shouldn't've.
说了一些不该说的话
Come on. You know these guys were born after the outbreak.
拜托 你知道这些人 是在疫情爆发后出生的
Never learned how to argue. They just start swingin'.
从没学过怎么吵架 只会直接动手
Fuckin' 19-year-old pieces of shit.
该死的１９岁小屁孩
It's a miracle you're alive.
你还活着真是奇蹟
It's a miracle any of us are alive.
我们所有人还能活着都是奇蹟
These aren't new.
这不是新的伤口
No.
对
I was in FEDRA lockup all day.
我在对策局的监狱关了一整天
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
总之这不重要
- I need you to take a breath. - What?
－我要你深呼吸 －什么事
- Joel-- - What?
－乔尔 －什么事
The guys who jumped me were with Robert.
打我的人跟罗伯特是一伙的
He sold our battery to someone else.
他把我们的电池卖给别人了
Nothing's lost. Shit like this is gonna happen.
没有损失 这种鸟事难免会发生
Now we just shake it off,
现在我们得振作起来
and we go get our cards back, or the battery.
把配给卡或电池拿回来
I need the battery, Tess. Truck's no good without one,
我需要电池 泰丝 没有电池 卡车就没用
and if I don't get to Tommy soon, he's gonna die out there.
如果我不快点找到汤米 他会死在外面
Okay, fuck it. We get our money back and the battery.
好吧 管他的 我们拿回我们的钱和电池
But, Joel, listen, Robert is terrified of you.
但乔尔 听着 罗伯特很怕你
So, you march outta here all Clint Eastwood, he's gonna get wind of it and skip.
要是你像克林伊斯威特一样冲出去 他会听到风声然后落跑
I need you to take a breath.
我要你先冷静下来
- Who'd he sell it to? - Don't know.
－他卖给谁了  －不知道
- Well, where is he? - Don't know.
－他在哪里  －不知道
Yet.
还不知道
But we're gonna find out, quietly.
但我们要悄悄查出来
Understand?
明白吗
Now I promised Robert that you wouldn't hurt him.
我向罗伯特保证过你不会伤害他
But I would very much like for you to hurt him.
但我非常希望你狠狠教训他一顿
So let's go hunt that motherfucker down,
所以我们去追杀那个混蛋
and get our battery and our truck,
拿回我们的电池和卡车
and then we'll go find Tommy. All right?
然后我们去找汤米 好吗
All right.
好
The team in place at Southeast 3?
东南区的小队就位了吗
I held them back.
我要他们暂停行动
I have some questions.
我有几个问题
Okay.
好
We've been blowing up meaningless FEDRA targets spread out all over the QZ, for two weeks.
我们过去两周一直在漫无目的地 炸毁隔离区各地的对策局目标
We've already lost four people, and we're--
我们已经失去了四个人 我们…
What's the point of this?
这有什么意义
Is that your question?
这就是你的问题吗
That's one of them.
那是其中之一
My answer is to follow fuckin' orders.
我的答案是你服从命令就好
And why do you have some random girl locked in a room?
你为什么把一个陌生女孩关在房里
And the guys you have guarding her won't tell me shit?
你派去看守她的人什么都不告诉我
Our people are asking what's going on, and I don't know what to tell them.
我们的人在问怎么回事 我不知道该怎么回答
Tell them to follow fuckin' orders.
叫他们服从命令
You two, go to Southeast 3. Now.
你们两个去东南三 立刻去
- Kim. - Marlene.
－琴 －玛琳
We are in a war against a military dictatorship
我们在对抗一个军事独裁政权
to restore democracy and freedom. Does that sound about right?
致力于恢复民主和自由 对吗
- Yes? - Are we winning? Are we beating FEDRA here?
－对 －我们赢了吗 有打败对策局吗
Are the Fireflies beating FEDRA anywhere? - Rebellion takes time.
－火萤有在哪里打败对策局吗  －反抗需要时间
- You fight for 20 years and you get nowhere, you're not a rebellion.
如果你奋斗了２０年却一无所获 你就不能算是反抗军
Just spray paint.
只不过是在到处涂鸦而已
We're not hitting FEDRA "all over" the QZ.
我们不是在隔离区内 漫无目的地攻击对策局
We hit 'em here, here, here, here, here.
我们攻击这里…
Where are we right now?
我们现在在哪里
I want FEDRA everywhere but here.
我故意要对策局的人散布各处 除了这里以外
I want them as distracted as possible
我要他们尽可能分心
because tonight, every Firefly in Boston is gonna gather in this building,
因为今晚 波士顿所有火萤成员 都会聚集在这栋大楼
and we are gonna leave the QZ. Permanently.
我们要永远离开隔离区
- We're quitting?
我们要放弃
- No. We're taking that random girl locked in that room west.
不 我们要带那个 被关在房里的陌生女孩去西部
From our guy in the radio tower in Salem.
这是我们在塞冷无线电塔的人传来的
Is this real?
这是真的吗
I believe it is.
我相信是的
Keep it quiet.
别声张
Whatever you need. Whatever it takes.
你需要什么都行 不惜一切代价
We'll get her where she needs to go.
我们会送她去该去的地方
Hey, friend.
朋友
Don't worry. I don't want anything.
别担心 我什么都不要
But if you're feelin' lost--
但如果你感到迷失…
You tell me to "look for the light" and I'll break your jaw.
叫我寻找光明 我就打断你的下巴
Well, it cost us a couple of cards, but we got him.
虽然花了我们几张配给卡 但我们逮到他了
He's supposedly takin' the battery to a red-tagged building.
据说他要把电池 送到一栋有红色记号的大楼
But get this, corner of Stillman and Cross.
但大楼位于 史提尔曼街和克罗斯街的转角
The one Miguel used to use.
米盖尔以前用的那栋
Yeah, I'm thinkin' so.
对 应该是
We can take the subway tunnel under Haymarket,
我们可以走干草市场下面的地铁隧道
get into the building from below, and take Robert by surprise.
从下面进入大楼 突袭罗伯特
Pay this fucker back.
我们狠狠还击
Oh, my God.
拜托
Agh! You fucker!
可恶
One, two, three, four--
一 二 三 四
You're not scared.
你不怕吗
Then unlock me.
那就把我解开
How about we start with "thank you"?
不如先说声谢谢吧
For what?
谢什么
For saving your life?
救你一命
I am the one who told 'em not to shoot you, if you recall.
如果你还记得的话 是我要他们别对你开枪的
- Yeah.
是喔
Why did you stop them?
你为什么要阻止他们
We'll get to that.
这个待会再说
So, Veronica,
那么 薇若妮卡
how ya feelin'?
你感觉如何
The same.
老样子
Is it gonna happen?
我会发病吗
No.
不会
So, can I go?
那我可以走了吗
I won't tell anyone about any of this. I swear.
我不会把这里的事告诉任何人 我发誓
Where you gonna go? Back to FEDRA military school?
你要去哪 回对策局军校
- You that anxious to be a soldier?
你那么想当军人吗
- You think I chose that place?
你以为我乐意去那里吗
They put me there when I was a baby.
我还是婴儿的时候 他们就把我送去那里了
It's for orphans.
那是收容孤儿的地方
"They" didn't put you there.
不是他们把你送去那里的
I did.
是我
Ellie.
艾莉
You my fucking mom or something?
你该不会是我妈吧
Do I look like your mom?
我看起来像你妈吗
Nooo, you do not.
不像
My name is Marlene.
我叫玛琳
I'm the leader of the Fireflies in the Boston QZ.
我是波士顿隔离区的火萤首领
Why would a terrorist dump me with FEDRA?
为什么恐怖分子 会把我丢给对策局
Because it's where you'd be safest,
因为那是你最安全的地方
and you were safe there until you decided to sneak out.
你本来确实很安全 直到你决定偷溜出去
And "terrorist"?
恐怖分子
Was Riley a terrorist?
莱莉是恐怖分子吗
Why won't you let me go home?
你为什么不让我回家
Because you have a greater purpose than any of us could've ever imagined.
因为你有更远大的目标 远超过任何人的想像
So we're leaving tonight, and we're taking you with us.
所以我们今晚就要离开 而且我们要带你一起走
- He's here. - Five minutes.
－他来了 －给我五分钟
What I'm about to tell you cannot be repeated to anyone.
我接下来要告诉你的事情 不能告诉任何人
Because if you do,
因为如果你说了
I assure you
我向你保证…
you will die.
你会死
Okay.
好
Ready? Yeah.
－准备好了吗  －好了
That's the one.
就是这个
Oh fuck.
可恶
Oh shit.
该死
This one's done.
这已经死了
Yeah. I know.
对 我知道
I just-- I wasn't expecting it.
我只是一时被吓到
Take it he wasn't down here last time?
我猜上次他不在这里
No.
不在
You think he came down after he was infected?
你觉得他是被感染后下来的吗
Well, maybe down here is where he was infected.
或者他就是在这里被感染的
Let's keep movin'.
我们继续走吧
It's like they reframed the whole structure.
看来他们把整栋建筑的构架都改了
Probably in the '80s.
可能是在１９８０年代做的
Everyone was cutting down on apartment sizes to sell more condos.
大家都缩减公寓大小 以便卖出更多单位
"This has been 'Construction Corner' with Joel Miller."
欢迎收看“乔尔米勒的工地现场”
How far up we goin'?
我们要爬多高
This far.
这么高
So, this opens into the hallway.
这里通往走廊
What the fuck? Someone put a piano in front of this?
搞什么 有人把钢琴放在这前面吗
You smell that?
你有闻到吗
Yeah, gunpowder.
有 火药味
Tess.
泰丝
Well, the battery's no good.
电池不能用了
And he still tried to sell it.
他还是想卖掉
Twice.
还卖两次
You greedy fuck.
你这个贪心的混蛋
Oh God.
天啊 就…
Shit, come on.
该死 加把劲
Fuck.
该死
Joel?
乔尔
Marlene?
玛琳
- You okay? - Yeah.
－你没事吧  －没事
Ellie. Ellie!
艾莉…
- Oh shit! - No, it's okay. I'll be all right.
－该死 －不 没关系 我会没事的
And you can't be stupid like this.
你不能干这种蠢事
So this is who Robert screwed us over with?
罗伯特就是为了你摆我们一道
The Che Guevara of Boston?
波士顿的革命英雄
War must be goin' pretty shitty for you to be buying from scumbags like him.
战况一定很不顺利 你才会跟他这种人渣买货
Yeah, it kinda has been.
算是吧
The merch was bad, and he obviously didn't take "fuck off" for an answer.
货很烂 但他显然不接受“滚蛋”这个答案
- Gimme my knife. - What do you need a car battery for?
－把刀子还给我 －你要汽车电池做什么
- Don't. - Not at her.
－不行 －不要指着她
Point it at me.
指着我
And to answer your question, I need it for a better reason than you do.
至于你问题的答案 我需要它有比你更好的理由
No offense, but Tommy's just one man.
无意冒犯 但汤米只是一个人
- It's our business to know things. -"To know things."
－掌握情报是我们的职责 －掌握情报
You're the cause of it. You turned my own brother against me.
你就是罪魁祸首 是你让我弟弟跟我翻脸
- Okay, Joel. - That was a lot of gunfire.
－好 乔尔 －枪声很响亮
- FEDRA's gonna be on the way. - I know.
－对策局肯定在路上了 －我知道
We were gonna move Ellie outta the zone tonight.
我们今晚本来要把艾莉带出隔离区
But we won't make it anywhere like this. Not for a while anyway.
但这样我们哪也去不了 暂时还不行
So now I'm thinkin',
所以我在想…
you're gonna do it. - The hell we are.
－你们带她走 －我们才不要
- I'm not goin' with them! - Let me take her.
－我不要跟他们走 －让我带她走
- Tess, we don't have time for this. You don't have time?
－泰丝 我们没时间扯这些 －是吗
- Who is she? - To you? She's cargo.
－她是谁  －对你们来说 她是货物
We don't smuggle people.
我们不走私人
Sorry. - I can do it.
－抱歉 －我可以的
- Kim, you don't have a fuckin' ear on your fuckin' head. Could you please?
琴 你是没长耳朵吗 给我闭嘴
There's a team of Fireflies waiting for her at the old State House.
有一群火萤的人在旧议会大厦等她
I know what's out there.
我知道外面有什么
We were going with an entire squadron for that very reason.
所以我们派了一个小队过去
But now I don't have a truck, I don't have a squadron,
但现在我没有卡车 没有小队
FEDRA's five minutes away. What I do have is you.
对策局再五分钟就到了 我只有你们
And I know what you're both capable of.
我很清楚你们两个的能耐
For better or worse.
无论好坏
What are they capable of?
他们有什么能耐
You get her there safely, and they'll give you what you need.
把她平安送到那里 他们会满足你们的需求
Not just a battery. The whole thing.
不只是电池 而是所有东西
Fueled-up truck, guns, supplies, all of it. I swear.
加满油的卡车 枪 物资 通通都有 我发誓
I swear.
我发誓
Asshole!
混蛋
You trust her?
你相信她吗
No, me neither, but she seems desperate.
我也不信 但她好像很急
Firefly vehicle usually means repurposed FEDRA stuff.
火萤的车通常是用对策局的车改装的
So better-than-decent chance makin' it to Tommy in one of those.
所以有很大的机会能开到汤米那里
The second we hand that kid over--
我们把那小鬼交出去就走
Y'all talk it through, but please remember that I'm bleeding out.
你们好好谈谈 但请记住 我血流不止
Okay. Here's the deal.
好 这样吧
We'll get her to your crew at the State House.
我们会把她交给你们在议会大厦的人
But before we hand her over, they give us everything that we want.
但在我们交出她之前 他们必须给我们想要的一切
If not, we kill her, there and then. - Deal.
－否则我们就当场杀了她 －成交
- Really? That fast?
真的吗 想都不想
You are all that matters. My team will not jeopardize that.
你才是最重要的 我的团队不会危及这一点
Remember what I told you? Now go get your backpack.
记住我跟你说的话 去拿你的背包
Now, Ellie.
现在就去 艾莉
Let's go.
我们走
Joel,
乔尔
don't fuck this up.
别搞砸
Please.
拜托
Give us a minute, all right?
给我们一分钟 好吗
What the fuck?!
搞什么
So, what's the plan?
计划是什么
There's not a lot of options.
选择不多
There's the short way or the long way.
不是走捷径就是绕远路
The short way is pretty much...
走捷径会是一场恶梦
That leaves the long way.
我们绕远路吧
Things look bad, we'll come up with something.
我们只要安全抵达就好
We'll have to drop, head to Bill and Frank's.
交货之后去比尔和法兰克家
Stock up on anything we may need.
囤积一切我们可能需要的东西
THE BILLBOARD BOOK OF NUMBER 1 HITS
（告示牌排行榜冠军单曲全集）
We leave after dark. Stay with the kid.
我们天黑后出发 你跟那小鬼一起待在这
Wait. Why do I have to--
等等 为什么是我
Tess.
泰丝…
60 - NOTHING IN
（６０ 没有）
70 - NEW STOCK 80 - X
（７０ 新货 ８０ Ｘ）
So, who's Bill and Frank?
比尔和法兰克是谁
The radio's a smuggling code, right?
收音机播的歌是走私暗号 对吧
'60s song, they don't have anything new,
１９６０年代的歌代表他们没有新货
'70s, they got new stuff.
１９７０年代的歌就代表他们有新货
What's '80s?
那１９８０年代呢
What are you doing? - Killin' time.
－你在做什么  －打发时间
- Well, what am I supposed to do? I'm sure you'll figure that out.
－那我要做什么  －我相信你可以自己想到
Your watch is broken.
你的手表坏了
You mumble in your sleep.
你睡觉时会说梦话
I've never been on the other side of the Wall.
我从没去过围墙的另一边
Look how dark it is.
你看那里有多黑
You guys go out there a lot?
你们常去外面吗
- I guess. - When was the last time?
－大概吧 －上次是什么时候
Maybe a year. What's it matter? But you know where to go.
－大概一年前 有差吗  －但你们知道该怎么走
So we're gonna be okay.
所以我们会没事的
Yeah.
对
So what's the deal with you anyway? You some kinda bigwig's daughter or somethin'?
所以你到底是怎么回事  某个大人物的女儿吗
Something like that.
差不多吧
The radio came on when you were sleeping.
你睡着时收音机响了
What? What was the song?
什么 是什么歌
He kept sayin', like, "Wake me up before you go-go"?
歌词一直重复“走之前叫醒我”
Shit.
该死
Gotcha.
骗到你了
'80s means trouble.
１９８０年代的歌代表有麻烦
Code broken.
破解了
Listen--
听着…
The spot under Lancaster looks good.
兰开斯特街底下看起来不错
- You got a jacket in your pack? - Yeah.
－你背包里有外套吗  －有
Okay, get it. It's time to go.
好 去拿 该走了
...mandatory curfew to fight infection and insurrection.
遵守强制宵禁 对抗感染与叛乱
Holy shit. I'm actually outside.
天啊 我真的跑到外面来了
- Jesus Christ. - Shit.
－天啊 －该死
Okay, we're gonna take the left edge around the buffer zone.
好 我们靠左边走缓冲区
You stay close and you follow my lead.
你要跟紧 听我指挥
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
好 当然
Let's go.
我们走
What the hell?
搞什么
Hey, hey! Don't, don't, don't move.
－不准动 －该死
Don't move!
不准动
You gotta be shittin' me.
你在开玩笑吧
- Okay, let's talk this out.
好 我们商量一下
- Turn around. - Hold on--
－转过去 跪下 －等等
- Get on your fuckin' knees. Get on your fuckin' knees! - Now hold on--
－给我跪下 －等一下
- What did I fuckin' tell you, man? I said stay the fuck home.
我是怎么跟你说的 我叫你待在家里
Get on your knees!
跪下
Just get on your knees, just get on your knees.
跪下就是了 跪下
Listen, you let us do this run, we'll split the cards with you.
听着 你让我们干这一票 我们就跟你平分配给卡
- Will you? - Yeah.
－是吗  －对
I'm so blessed. Hands on your head. Eyes forward.
那我还真是太幸运了 手放在头上 眼睛看前面
Hands on your head!
手放在头上
- Really, man? - Yep. We're doin' this by the book.
－真的吗 老兄  －对 我们得照规矩来
Jesus Christ.
天啊
All right. What about three-quarters?
好吧 给你四分之三如何
Unauthorized exit. They'll hang you for that.
未经授权离开 你们会被吊死的
Fine. Everythin' off of this run, and half off on all of the pills.
好吧 这一票全给你 所有的药都半价
Half off? All off.
半价 全部免钱
Risk my job for half off. Outta your fuckin' mind--
拿我的工作冒险只换半价  你真是疯了
Ellie, Ellie! - Ellie, what the--  - Fuckin'
－艾莉…搞什么  －该死
bitch! Fuck!
臭小鬼 可恶
Get out of the fuckin' way!
给我让开
We can fix this. Move.
－我们可以解决的 －让开
Move.
让开
No, no! No, I'm not sick! - Joel!
－不 我没病 －乔尔
Joel, Joel! - I am not sick! I'm not sick!
－我没病 你看 －乔尔…
Look! Look! This is three weeks old.
你看 这是三星期前的
Nobody lasts more than a day!
没有人能撑过一天
Does this look a day old to you?
这看起来像一天前的吗
- You would've killed me! - I should fucking kill you!
－你们会杀了我的 －我真该杀了你
- When did it happen? - It doesn't matter! You have to trust me!
－什么时候的事  －这不重要 你们得相信我
They're gonna catch us if we don't run!
我们再不跑的话 他们会抓到我们的
Joel, we gotta move. We gotta move, Joel!
乔尔 我们得走了…
Joel!
乔尔
WARNING: BIOLOGICAL CONTAMINATION AREA DO NOT PROCEED
（联邦灾害对策局 警告 生物污染区）